Finding Aid for HIV/AIDS Resource Center Records, 1986-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
HIV/AIDS Resource Center Records 1986-2003
HIV/AIDS Resource Center.
2 linear feet.
0655 Bf 2
Established in 1986 in Ann Arbor and Ypsilanti, Michigan as Wellness Networks, Inc.-Huron Valley, the organization provides HIV and AIDS related services and information. The name of the organization was changed to HIV/AIDS Resource Center in 1993. Board meeting minutes and agendas, correspondence and memoranda, activity files, newspaper articles, and related records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was acquired from the organization (donor no. 9721 ) on April 25, 2006.
The record group is open. However, access to the records requires the researcher to sign an access agreement preserving confidentiality of names recorded in the files.
The HIV/AIDS Resource Center (HARC) was established in 1986 under its original name, Wellness Networks, Inc. -- Huron Valley (WNI-HV). The organization started in response to the growing threat of the HIV/AIDS epidemic in the local metro-Detroit region. In 1993, they changed their name to HARC to prevent confusion with other local non-profit organizations. Despite the name change, the HARC has consistently served the local metro-Detroit area by promoting positive health practices and lifestyles, by providing information about HIV/AIDS, and by providing direct care services to the local community. HARC is still an active organization and more information can be found on their website: http://comnet.org/harc/index.html.
The record group is split into two series: The Wellness Networks, Inc. -- Huron Valley series and the HIV/AIDS Resource Center (HARC). The first series consists of records such as meeting minutes, bylaws, press releases, and financial statements, and they document the establishment and the early period of the organization. The second series consist of board meeting minutes, outreach activity plans, speakers' schedules, and committee activities.
Subjects:
HIV/AIDS Resource Center.; AIDS (Disease)--Michigan.; HIV infections--Michigan.; Wellness Networks-Huron Valley.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ypsilanti (Mich.)
- Wellness Networks, Inc. -- Huron Valley
  The Wellness Networks, Inc. -- Huron Valley series (1986-1993) include papers documenting the establishment and the early years of the organization. Details of the group's activities can be found in the Board Meeting Minutes folders.
  - Board Meeting Agendas, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Board Meeting Minutes, 1986-1993, 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Bylaws and Proposals, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - Bylaws, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Charitable Trust Application, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Communications, Agenda Columns, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Communications, Press Releases, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Committee Descriptions, 1986-1988 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1989, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Financial Statements, 1986-1988 (Box 1)
  - Fundraising, Bach Benefit, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Fundraising, Letters, 1987-1989 (Box 1)
  - Information Updates, 1986-1989 (Box 1)
  - Washtenaw AIDS Education Network (WAEN) meetings, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Wellness Consultant, 1990 (Box 1)
- HIV/AIDS Resource Center (HARC)
  The HIV/AIDS Resource Center (HARC) series (1993-2000) consists of records documenting the organization's activities in the metro-Detroit area. Accounts of their activities are recorded in the organization's Board Meeting Minutes folders.
  - Advertising, 1999 (Box 1)
  - AIDS Walk
    - Disks, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Planning, 1996-1998 (Box 1)
    - Programs, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
    - Publicity, 1996-1998 (Box 1)
  - Board Committee Projects, 1994-1997 (Box 1)
  - Board Meetings, 1993-1995, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Board Meetings, 1996-2000, 11 folders (Box 2)
  - Board Members Biography, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Church Affiliates, 1989-1996 (Box 2)
  - Committees
    - Education Committee, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Fundraising Committee, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
    - Personnel Committee, 1997 (Box 2)
  - General Information, Organizational Chart, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Harm Reduction Plans, undated (Box 2)
  - Interoffice Memos, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - Interoffice Memos, 1996-2000, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - HIV Testing, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1994-1997 (Box 2)
  - Speaker's Bureau, 1994-1999, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Strategic and Project Plans, 1999-2000 (Box 2)